Guide to the Stanford University, Program in International Security Studies, Honors Theses SC4-6530
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in International Security Studies, Honors Theses
2002-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Center for International Security and Cooperation
SC4-6530
1.25 Linear Feet (31 volumes in 3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in International Security Studies.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Center for International Security and Cooperation in 2005. Additional theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in International Security Studies.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Security, International.; Student papers.; Stanford University. Center for International Security and Cooperation
- Theses, 2003-2005; Accession ARCH-2005-237
  - Chestnut, Sheena E., The "Sopranos State"?: North Korean Involvement in Criminal Activity and Implications for International Security., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Cieslewicz, John, Attacks and Accidents: Policy to Protect the Power Grid's Critical Computing and Communication Needs., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Zack, Roman and British Experiences with Maritime Piracy and Implications for Combating Terrorism Today., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Corley, Anne-Marie, Lifting the Fog: Trends and Methodology in Friendly Fire Research., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Craig, Dana Lynn, Unintended Consequences: Signaling Failures During the Cold War., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Everett, Andrea, Allegiance and Accession: Expansion of the Transatlantic Battleground into Central and Eastern Europe., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Gaston, Erica, Rethinking European security: from new world order to new defense initiative, 1989-2003., May 23, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Ghani, Tarek Fouad, Between War and Peace: State-building in Post-Taliban Afghanistan., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Tanya L., A genocide missed: international policy failure in Rwandan reconstruction., May 23, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Greninger, Alex, Beyond the last move: developing biodefenses to engineered anthrax and smallpox. (Box 1)
  - Gupta, Nidhi, "An Arsenal fit for the Gods": analyzing the forces driving India's intercontinental ballistic missile program., May 23, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Haldeman, Zachary, New roles for nuclear weapons: bunker busting and agent defeat., May 20, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Kliman, Daniel M., Japan's defense policy in the post-9/11 world: toward a "normal" nation., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Larson, Bradley, Soft Powers: US Foreign Aid Post-9/11., May 31, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Lengsfelder, J. Savannah, At Home in Our World: Evoling Ideologies in American Foreign Policy., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Lewis, Frances S., The Yellow Light Reactor: An Explanation of the Stop and Go Progress at Bushehr., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Mallipeddi, Meena S., Rethinking International Relations: the United States, the Great Powers, and the Changing International System., May 23, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Marsh, Victor Lerun II, A Responsibility to Consult?: Local Policy Ownership During Transitional Governance., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - McLaughlin, Jessica, A Bayesian Updating Model for Intelligence Analysis: A Case Study of Iraq's Nuclear Weapons Program., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Platt, Erica S., Losing Balance: The Politics of U. S. Encryption Regulation During the Clinton Administration., May 29, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Vaynman, Jane, Nunn-Lugar Programs: Post-Cold War Security Cooperation and an Emerging Security Framework., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Vodopyanov, Anya, A Watchful Eye Behind the Iron Curtain: The U. S. Military Liaison Mission in East Germany, 1953-61., May 21, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Williams, Christopher, Closing the Nuclear Fuel Cycle: A Component Based Analysis of Options for Spent Fuel Management., May 31, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Zhu, Ming, Power and Cooperation: Understanding the Road Towards a Truth Commission., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Zukerman, Sarah, Repression and rebellion: the roots of conflict in El Salvador and peace in Honduras., May 23, 2003 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Golabeck-Goldman, Michele Gabrielle, Adequacy of U.S. hospital preparedness for mass casualty incidents: critical lessons from the Israeli experience., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Grace K., The North Korean nuclear program: a revisionist history., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Keith, Beyond 'electronic Pearl Harbor': lessons for averting a digital September 11., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Burton, Brian, Counterinsurgency principles and US military effectiveness in Iraq., 2007 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-022
  - Epstein, Alison, "Linking arms: The Iraq war inquiry and the future of the UK-US special relationship", 2012 May 21 (Box 1)
  - Thompson, Reagan, "Assessing the Chinese influence in Ghana, Angola, and Zimbabwe: the impact of politics, partners, and petro", 2012 May 21 (Box 1)